健康跑登记处在A楼
They're doing the race registration over in "A" Wing.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我侄女佐伊
This is my niece Zoe.
你想去看他们搬卸放在爱心宠物园的小动物吗
Do you want to go see them unload the animals for the petting zoo?
气球真好看
Hey, I like the balloons.
孩子们  能听见我说话吗
Girls, can you hear me?
养兵千日用兵一时  各位
Every bit of training we've had was for today, boys.
如果有一个汽车炸弹  可能还有第二个
If there's one car bomb, there's probably a second.
看起来跟当时俄克拉荷马市的情况一样
It looks just like Oklahoma City.
道森呢
Where's Dawson?
-她进去了  -道森在里面吗
- She went inside. - Dawson's in there?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
就是擦伤了一点而已
Yeah, it's--it's just a little scratch.
伊莫金  快来人啊
Imogene! We need help over here!
加比  有人吗
Gabby! Hello?
她才九岁啊
She's only 9 years old!
你来救我了
You came.
我们发现了第二枚炸弹
We found our second bomb.
夏伊  找到道森了
Shay, we got Dawson.
夏伊
Shay?
快来人
Help!
这里需要医生
We need some help over here!
天呐
Oh, my God.
她失血过多
Oh, she's lost a lot of blood.
帮我把她抱到治疗诊断区
Help me get her into one of these bays.
好
All right.
马上准备静脉注射
I'm going to need to get an I.V. started.
好
Right away.
第一枚炸弹于八点整爆炸
First bomb detonated 8:00 a.m. on the dot.
第二枚被放在一辆租赁汽车里
Second bomb located in a rental car.
现在车还在那边
Car is still there.
-谁拆除的炸弹  -我们
- Who dismantled the bomb? - We did.
去看看
Check it out.
如果有线索  马上跟我汇报
If they got anything, I want to be notified first.
好
Yeah.
-多少人确认死亡  -18人死亡
- How many confirmed dead? - 18 dead...
15人情况危急  还有三名工作人员下落不明
15 in critical condition, 3 employees unaccounted for.
慈善赛跑的报名登记
The sign-ups for the charity race
在炸弹爆炸前刚开始
had just started before the bomb detonated.
可能废墟下面还有人被埋
We may have more civilians buried beneath the rubble,
但现在无法确认
but there's no real way of knowing right now.
负责此案的联调局特别探员让所有指挥人员
FBI special agent in charge wants all the bosses
去指挥中心
in the command center.
好  大家都进去
All right, everybody inside.
博伊特
Voight...
这种事只有禽兽才干得出来
Animals did this.
我们一定会抓到他们
We'll get 'em.
有什么发现吗
Anything?
应该没什么希望了  但大家还在挖
Not much left to recover, but we're still digging.
好吧
All right.
知道是谁干的吗
You know who did it?
不知道  调查才刚刚开始
No, we're just getting started.
一定要抓住他们
Find 'em.
听到请大声回答
Call out if you can hear me!
我们该先找谁谈  埃尔
Who do we talk to first, Al?
爆炸发生时在场并且活着的人
Whoever was closest to the blast and is still alive.
芝加哥警署情报部
Intelligence, C.P.D.
大家安静  安静  听我说
Quiet then, okay, everybody, listen up.
听我说
Listen up!
我是威廉·格拉夫
My name is William Graff.
联邦调查局派来的
I'm with the FBI.
我需要大家的帮助
I need all your help,
我也知道  大家都会积极提供帮助
and I know you're all eager to provide it.
但首先要注意
First rule...
一切都必须经过我
Everything goes through me.
现在我想知道目前的情况
Okay, I want to go over what we know right now.
血压上来了
Blood pressure coming up.
佐伊那边有消息吗
Any word on Zoe?
没有
Nothing.
生命体征稳定  无大脑活动
Vital signs are stable, no brain activity.
继续给她用生命维持系统  我去和她姐姐谈谈
Keep her on life support. I need to go talk to her sister.
-佐伊有消息吗  -还没有
- Anything on Zoe? - Not yet.
霍莉
Holly...
不
Oh, no.
我有这个准备
I've made this speech.
不用再说了
Don't say anymore.
天啊
Oh, God.
oh, God.
你妹妹还有呼吸
Your sister's still breathing,
但是有段时间没有大脑活动了
but there's been no brain activity for some time.
这么说她还活着
So she's alive.
我去看看她
I'm going to go see her.
阿利姆·阿尔·萨菲尔
Alim Al Safir,
叙利亚大使  来芝加哥进行秘密手术
Ambassador from Syria, is here for an off-the-books surgery.
我的人还有中情局格雷格·辛普森的人
My office and the office of Greg Simpson at CIA
会先从这个角度着手调查
will be spearheading this angle,
但如果你们有任何与此相关的信息
but if you encounter anything that waves near this,
记得跟我说
notify me.
我刚要做手术...
I was going to do the transplant...
给叙利亚大使做手术吗
On the Syrian ambassador?
好
All right.
你有没有发现什么异常情况
Did you see anything that looked out of place?
还记不记得
Do you remember?
-他手底下有好几个人  -好几个人
- Oh, he had his guys. - Guys?
他是个大使  身边带着保镖
He's an ambassador. He has guys.
接下来我就只知道
And the next thing I knew,
地面像发生地震一样摇晃
the ground shook like it was an earthquake.
一瞬间我还以为自己在旧金山呢
I thought for a second I was back in San Francisco.
威尔海特医生  7632
Dr. Willhite, 7632.
-威尔海特医生  7632  -去吧
- Dr. Willhite, 7632. - All right.
在这里工作的一名护理员
We also have an orderly who works here
还跟穆斯林激进分子有关系
with distant ties to a radical Muslim group.
我帮不了你  不是我做的
I can't help you. I didn't do it.
我也没看到是谁  我得专注于自己能做的事
I didn't see who did it, and I've got to focus on what I can do,
也就是尽可能拯救生命
which is save as many lives and limbs as I possibly can.
-知道了  谢谢  -好
- I got it. Thank you. - All right.
有两个家伙  戴着棒球帽太阳镜
There were two guys-- baseball caps on, sunglasses.
我注意到他们是因为当时大家都在
I noticed because everyone else was walking
往帐篷那边走  去报名登记
toward the tent to sign up for the race.
但他们却往反方向走
They were walking away from it.
他们还有什么特征吗
And what else did you notice about them?
棕色皮肤  橄榄色  深色的头发
Tan skin... olive, dark hair for sure.
但说不清是西班牙裔还是阿拉伯人或意大利人
But could have been Hispanic or Arab or Italian.
我不知道
I don't know.
打扰了  格拉夫探员
Excuse me. Agent Graff?
我是芝加哥警署情报部的汉克·博伊特警长
Sergeant Hank Voight, intelligence, C.P.D.
你好
How you doing?
听着  我希望你能好好配合我的工作
Listen, I'm really going to need your help--
做好防御工作  好好盘问信息  谢谢
securing the perimeter, conducting interviews. Thanks.
我的队伍要做的可比盘问医院工作人员
My unit is gonna be doing a hell of a lot more
围警戒线什么的多了去了
than interviewing hospital staff and setting out pylons.
这事发生在我的城市  我的地盘
This happened in my city, on my soil.
别妨碍我
Don't get in my way.
给我几分钟时间  比利
I'm gonna need a few minutes, Billy.
一定要把这些家伙抓住
Catch these guys.
是啊
Yeah.
两名男子上了一辆白色四门轿车
Both males enter a white four-door sedan
从停车场东南出口出去了
and head out the southeast exit of the lot.
能找到监控视频吗
And we have security video?
保安部在受袭击区域
The security office was in the impact zone.
数据库毁了  根本无法恢复
Database is gone, as in gone gone.
第二辆装有炸弹的车
Second car with a bomb
是从密尔沃基一家停车场租来的
was rented out of some dirt-lot company in Milwaukee.
租赁协议上的名字和信用卡号是伪造的
The name and the credit card on the rental agreement came back bogus.
据那家公司的人说
And there's no security video at the company,
他们没有监控视频
or so they're saying.
密尔沃基警署正去那里调查
So Milwaukee P.D.'s heading there to investigate.
萨姆纳  你做卧底对付北约反抗份子的时候
Sumner, you dealt with all those antigovernment nutcases
和这些反政府的疯子
when you were working undercover
有过接触对吧
at the NATO protests, am I right?
-是的  -到处去找找线索
- That's right. - All right, beat the bushes.
伙计们  我刚听说了一件事
Hey, guys, I just heard.
爆炸发生的时候  伯吉斯在场
Burgess was here when it happened,
她侄女现在在重症加护病房
and her niece is in the I.C.U.
-情况有多糟糕  -不妙
- How bad? - Not good.
出事的是佐伊
It's Zoe...
她  她还是个孩子
She's, um-- she's an only child.
她  我姐姐和姐夫不在城里
Her-- my sister and her husband are out of town.
所以她才和我住在一起
That's why she's staying with me.
现在伊莫金
And now Imogene...
我们听说了  医生怎么说
We just heard. What did they say?
肝脏破裂
A ruptured liver.
她  我看到了一个名单  捐献者名单
She's-- there's a list or something, a donor list.
他们正在找和她匹配的人
They're trying to match.
知道是谁做的吗
Do we know who did it?
有人能从中获益吗
Anybody taking credit?
好吧
Okay...
鉴定室从二号炸弹胶带上找到了一枚指纹
The lab got a print off the duct tape of bomb number two.
是一个叫保罗·瓦茨的人的
Came back to a Paul Watts.
车辆定位系统最后定位在南拉勒米5225号
V.L.D. has him registered at 5225 South Laramie.
我弄到了一份强行搜查令
I secured a no-knock search warrant.
过一会儿再告诉联邦探员指纹的事
Give us five minutes before you notify the Feds about that print.
好的
Yeah.
你先出去看看周边情况吧
They need you out on the perimeter.
我没事
I'm okay.
还有一件事
One more thing--
第二枚炸弹设定的爆炸时间是晚上八点半
The second bomb was set to go off at 8:30 p.m.
设炸弹的人肯定是哪里弄错了
The bomber screwed up somewhere.
我们今天需要的不是许可
We're gonna ask for forgiveness
而是原谅  懂吗
instead of permission today, you understand?
我们没有理由放松下来
We're not slowing down for anything.
没有任何理由
I mean anything.
除非抓住这些混蛋
No one's gonna give a damn once these bastards are caught.
好了  都行动起来
All right, let's go.
有什么新情况就告诉我们  好吗
You let us know if anything changes, okay?
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
保罗·瓦茨最近在塔拉哈西的
Paul Watts-- most recently a dishwasher
一家龙虾餐馆做洗碗工
at a Red Lobster in Tallahassee.
没什么犯罪记录  几次持有毒品的指控
Minor sheet-- a couple possession charges,
酗酒闹事
D&D...
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
我...
I'm, uh...
我试着联系我爸爸通知他
I'm trying to get a hold of my father to notify him.
我的...
My, um...
我理解
I understand.
我建议移除她的生命维持设备
I'll recommend we take her off life support.
我会从医学原理上给他解释的
I'll explain it to him medically.
好的
Okay.
我们要找的就是他
All right, that's who we're looking for.
1-a号公寓
Apartment 1-a.
小心电线或陷阱
Okay, careful of wires or traps.
做好一切准备
Anything's possible.
什么情况
Hey, what's this?
手放方向盘上  手放方向盘上
Hands on the wheel! Hands on the wheel!
转头看着我  不许动
Turn your head and look at me! Don't move!
看着我
Keep your eyes on me.
不是他
It's not him.
安全
Clear.
这到底是在搞什么
What the hell is going on?
不好意思  祝您今天愉快
It's our bad. Have a nice day.
安全
Well, it's clean.
但是我没法保证什么
I can't make any guarantees, though.
保罗·瓦茨  芝加哥警署
Paul Watts! C.P.D.!
安全
Clear!
尸体
Body!
安全
Clear!
Clear.
-通知其他人  -好的
- Call it in. - All right.
这不是自杀  枪在右边
This wasn't a suicide. Gun's on the right.
手机和钱包别在皮带左侧
Cell phone clip and wallet are on the left side of the belt.
无枪口火舌灼伤痕迹
He has no burn from muzzle flash,
脸上没有弹药残渣
no gunshot residue on his face.
肯定是有人从五英尺开外枪杀了他
Somebody had to shoot him from five feet away.
然后布置了这一切
They set this up.
通知吉恩和萨姆纳
All right, call Jin and Sumner.
我要这人的一切信息
I want to know everything about this guy.
从他租借的第一张影碟
The first movie he rented
到他刚买的薄荷糖
right down to the last breath mint he bought.
事无巨细
Everything.
刚才发生了一起爆炸
There was an explosion.
你没准备
You weren't gonna tell anyone
告诉别人你受了重伤吗
about that enormous gash in your side?
我...
I...
我本来想说的  只是...
I kept meaning to. I just...
我不能停下来
I had to keep going.
我知道  我知道  但现在不用了
I know. I know. But not anymore.
你总是这么照顾我
Always looking out for me.
好好休息  好吗
Rest up, okay?
好的
Okay.
西弗莱德
Severide.
有两个年龄相仿的女孩
There were two little girls
应该是八岁左右吧
about the same age-- I think eight.
你知道她们得救了没有吗
Do you know if they made it?
我不知道...
I don't know. Um, it's...
现场情况不容乐观
It's bad out there.
好好休息  好吗
Just get some rest, okay?
胶带上发现了他的指纹
His prints were on the tape.
肯定是他的同伙杀了他
Whoever he was working with took him out.
鉴证组正在全面搜查他家
Crime scene is at his place doing a full workup.
关于我们在查的那个穆斯林护理员
The muslim orderly we've been looking into--
我们刚在他车的底盘里发现了
We just found traces of fertilizer
-少量肥料  -他跟这件事有什么关系
- in the bed of his truck. - How's he connected?
我们还没联系起来
We haven't put the dots together yet,
但我们现在主要查他
but he's our focus.
你继续盘问员工就好
Just keep interviewing staff.
查到什么了吗
What do you got?
吉恩把瓦茨和他的同事交叉匹配了
Jin did a cross-match on Watts for known associates.
-好吧  -瓦茨最近在浏览
- All right. - It turns out Watts was trolling the websites
某些大型反政府组织网站
of some pretty heavy-duty antigovernment groups.
我们查出了一些
We pulled the names of some people
他最近在频繁联系的人
that he had repeated contact with.
邮件具体内容
Haven't been able to actually
还未查出
access the contents of the emails.
但我查到邮箱地址了
I was just able to get addresses.
等等  等等  回去
Whoa. Wait a second. Wait a second. Go back.
回去  等等  别换
Go back. Wait, hold on, wait a sec.
没错  就是他  就是这个人
Yeah, that's him. That's the guy.
什么人
What guy?
就是他告诉我两个带着墨镜的
The guy who told me two dark-skinned guys
深色皮肤的人逃离了现场
in sunglasses were leaving the scene.
就是这个人
That's the guy.
他在这里
He's here.
谢谢你们的帮助
Thank you for everything,
你们太不容易了  我深表同情
And I am so sorry for what you guys have been through.
你们都是英雄
You're all heroes.
-帕特·沃恩  -是我
- Pat Vaughn? - Yeah?
能跟我走一趟吗
Would you mind coming with us for a minute?
我只是想出院
I just checked out.
我们还有几个问题要问
We just have a few follow-up questions.
当然
Of course.
Sure.
别轻举妄动
Take it easy!
放我走
I am walking out of here.
-退后  -别再犯错了  沃恩
- Back up! - Don't go any further, Vaughn.
-反正我一无所有  -好的
- I got nothing to lose. - Okay.
那你想要什么
What are you hoping to gain?
你真的觉得我会放任你逃走吗
Do you think we're gonna let you drive out of here?
我可一点都不怕杀人  特别是警察
I got no problem slitting a throat, especially a cop's.
-冷静  -退后
- Easy. - Back up!
好吧  发生什么事了
Okay, man. What's going on here?
我们只是想救人性命
We're just trying to save some people.
-闭嘴  -听着
- Shut up! - Listen...
我们好好谈谈  好吗
Let's just talk this out, all right?
你要想完好无损地走出去  没问题
You want to walk out of here, you can walk out of here.
不要再说了
Don't say another word!
-你还好吗  -趴下
- You all right? - Stay down.
-你没事吧  -没事  谢谢
- You okay? - Yeah. Thank you.
-谢谢  -给我安排一间房
- Thank you. - I need a room.
别动
Don't move.
-这人参与爆炸事件了吗  -应该是的
- This guy involved? - Looks like it.
站起来
On your feet.
可以把他带到城里任何一家消防局
You can bring him in to any firehouse in the city.
我们用五分钟就够了
We'll take five minutes, all right?
我们会让他招的  我保证
We'll get some answers from him, I promise.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
博伊特
Voight.
我看着他
I got him.
探员
Sir?
穆斯林护理员的嫌疑洗清了
The Muslim orderly checks out.
在他车里找到的肥料残留
The fertilizer residue found in his truck traces
是他家附近的一处社区花园里的
to a community garden in his neighborhood.
我们找到有用的线索了
Well, we're onto something here.
好  但我不能就这样让你
Yeah, I can't let you traipse off with our only lead,
带走唯一的线索去瞎折腾
doing god knows what at all hours.
给我三十分钟
All I need is 30 minutes.
你只有二十分钟
You got 20.
我的肩膀骨折了
My shoulder is broken.
我需要治疗
I demand medical treatment.
那场爆炸  十八人死亡
18 people died in that bomb blast...
楼上还有十几个人生命垂危
A dozen more clinging to their life upstairs...
包括一个我辖区内警察的
9-year-old girl who's a niece of a cop
九岁的侄女
in my district.
你最好全盘托出  供出你的同伙
You tell me everything you know, every participant...
因为你是个懦夫  沃恩
Because as a coward, Vaughn--
我知道你是个懦夫
And I know you're a coward,
因为你炸死了癌症爱心募捐者
'cause that's who lays bombs at cancer fund-raisers--
我会让你生不如死
You will not endure the pain
你肯定受不了那种痛苦
that I'm going to put you through.
我需要...
I need to see a...
现在我来告诉你我想要什么
Now, let me tell you what I need.
我要知道你们晚上八点半的计划
I need to know about 8:30 P.M.
先让我得到治疗再说
Once I get medical treatment.
沃恩说他和瓦茨都和一个
Vaughn said him and Watts were both hooked up
叫泰德·鲍威尔的人有联系
with a guy named Ted Powell.
泰德·鲍威尔  我听过这个名字
Ted Powell-- I know that name.
他是反政府分子中的重要人物
He was big in the antigovernment fringe.
他父亲也是
So was his dad.
瓦茨为什么会被杀
Why did Watts get killed?
沃恩和瓦茨两人各负责
Vaughn and Watts were both in charge
设置一个汽车炸弹
of setting off two separate car bombs.
两个炸弹本来都应该在今晚爆炸
Both bombs were supposed to go off tonight--
瓦茨的在八点  沃恩的在八点半
Watts at 8:00, Vaughn at 8:30.
瓦茨一定是弄错了他那个
Watts must've rigged his wrong,
所以今天早晨就爆炸了
'cause it went off this morning.
八点是芝加哥警署和芝加哥消防局
8:00 P.M. was gonna be the gala
高层联欢会的时间  对吗
for the C.P.D. and the C.F.D. brass, right?
是的
Right.
第一个炸弹是要袭击他们
First bomb was set to get them.
第二个炸弹是要袭击救援人员
Second bomb was set to get the first responders.
你还问出什么了
What else you get out of him?
沃恩说鲍威尔还有什么终极计划
Vaughn said that Powell had some master plan
没有告诉他
that he didn't share with him.
所以这事还没完
So this wasn't the end of it.
这就是鲍威尔
Here's Powell.
我在医院外的人群里看到过他
I saw him outside the hospital with the crowd.
他也在这里
He was here too.
好了  先去查查他父亲
All right, let's check out his dad.
凯西
Casey!
-加比怎么样了  -她没事
- How's Gabby? - She's fine.
她回家了  还有点惊吓
She's home--a little rattled still,
不过也能理解
but who can blame her?
-给  -谢谢  伙计
- Here. - Oh, thanks, man.
多谢你救她出来
Thanks for getting her out.
我告诉她  她欠我一打啤酒
I told her she owes me a 12-pack.
还有从废墟里救出的幸存者吗
Any more survivors pulled out from the rubble?
情况不妙
Doesn't look good.
我们看见了一个女人的手
We saw a woman's hand,
刚花了一个小时把她挖出来
spent the last hour digging her out.
是会计部的一个单身母亲
It was a single mom from accounting--
家里有两个孩子
two kids at home.
什么样的人才会做出这种事
Who would do something like this?
我已经有眉目了
I've got a pretty good idea.
十年前  弗兰克·鲍威尔
Ten years ago, Frank Powell,
你们很多人可能还记得
many of you will remember,
在坎卡基县外他的牧场里
was arrested after a two-day standoff
与警方僵持两天后被捕
at his ranch outside of Kankakee.
他妻子在交火中身亡
His wife died in the gun battle.
他现在在斯泰特维尔监狱服无期徒刑
The old man is doing life at Stateville.
我手下两个警探正在去审问他的路上
Two of my detectives are on route to interview him.
牧场被攻陷的时候泰德·鲍威尔就在那里
Ted Powell was there when the ranch was raided.
他在那一天失去了他的双亲
He lost his mother and his father that day.
自那以后
He has been a fixture
他一直是过激反政府网站的常客
on radical antigovernment websites ever since.
斯泰特维尔监狱人员记录
鲍威尔  就是他
Powell--correct.
好的  要多久以前的记录
Okay. How far back?
所有的都要  可以追朔到五年前吗
Far back as they go. Five years?
好的
Okay.
我需要得到上级的同意
I'm gonna just need my supervisor to approve.
他应该一会儿就回来
He should be back in--
你今天看新闻了吗  伙计
Have you been watching the news today, man?
需要我给你看遇难者名单吗
Do I need to run down a list of the dead?
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道今天在芝加哥医院发生了什么吗
You're aware of what happened at Chicago Med today?
我知道
I am.
你儿子泰德牵涉其中  有可能是主谋
Your son Ted was involved, possibly the mastermind,
不过你可能已经知道了
but you probably knew that.
这是你说的
So you allege.
听着  不管你和政府有什么问题
Look, whatever problems you've had with the government,
不管你失去过什么
whatever losses you've suffered,
都不能成为你儿子今天这些行为的借口
there's no way to excuse what your son did today.
我们有理由相信
Now, we have reason to believe
他的计划可能还有下一步
that there might be more to his plan, another step.
所以我们可以做笔交易
So we can work out a deal, okay?
这可是你提条件的好机会
It's a buyer's market right now.
你帮我们  我们就会帮你
You help us, and we'll help you.
我非常为他骄傲
I couldn't be more proud of him.
要知道有孩子被害死了
You know, children were killed.
还用我给你解释"附带损害"吗
I got to explain collateral damage to you?
我们是在战斗
We're in a war.
在战争中  总会有平民伤亡
And in a war, there are gonna be noncombatant casualties.
好吧
Okay.
你想要什么
What do you want?
总有什么是你想要的
There's got to be something you want.
你知道警察局是什么时候开始堕落的吗
You know when the police department started go south?
什么时候开始让少数裔也能加入的吗
When they started letting minorities in.
要还是不要  你想不想谈交易
Yes or no? You want to make a deal?
因为以前  所有警察都是白人的时候
'Cause before, see, when all the cops were white,
你可以像正常人一样和他们说话
you could talk to them like a normal person.
但是你让一个少数裔进来
But you get a minority in there,
然后他们就各种愤懑
and there's all this resentment
从历史问题到个人缺点
from historical and personal shortcomings
都跑到台面上来了
that comes to the fore.
现在该是他们
Now's their big chance
滚回他们的压迫者那里去的时候了
to get back at their oppressors.
你是说像这样吗
You mean like this?
我不管你需要做什么
I don't care what you have to do.
不管  你给我一个准确时间
No, you give me an exact time.
-我现在就要  -霍斯特德
- I need it now. - Halstead.
怎么了  等一下
Yeah. Hold on.
我觉得大家需要看看这个
I think everyone's gonna want to see this.
好了  好了  安静  安静  开始
Okay, okay, settle down. Settle down. Hit it.
泰德·鲍威尔刚刚
Ted Powell just posted this
在一个反政府网站上发布了这个
on a fringe antigovernment website.
2004年  我的家人在伊利诺伊州
In 2004, my family's home in Kankakee, Illinois--
坎卡基县家里遭到了芝加哥警署的
we came under attack, without justification,
非正当攻击
by the Chicago Police Department.
他们向我们开火  我们家被大火吞没
We were fired upon, and our home was engulfed in flames.
芝加哥消防局袖手旁观  无所作为
The Chicago Fire Department stood by and did nothing.
我母亲那天死了
My mother died that day,
我父亲被抓进监狱
and my father sits in prison.
我等芝加哥警署和芝加哥消防局认错
I have waited ten years for the C.P.D. and C.F.D.
并撤销对我父亲的全部指控已经等了十年
to admit wrongdoing and to drop all charges against my father.
我不会再等下去了
I will wait no longer.
我在此向芝加哥警署
I'm declaring war on the Chicago Police Department
和芝加哥消防局宣战
and Chicago Fire Department.
如果你是这两个部门的一员  你就有危险
If you are a member of either department, you are not safe.
如果你是这两个部门成员的家属
If you are a family member of someone in either department,
你也不安全
You are not safe.
这只是开始
This is just the beginning.
我警告过你们了
You've been warned.
好  知道了  我再打给你
Yep, I got it. I'll call you back.
一个名叫赖安·威克斯的人在过去半年
A Ryan Wilcox visited Powell's dad in prison
三次去监狱探访了鲍威尔的父亲
three times in the last six months.
琳德赛调查了他一下
Lindsay did a workup on him.
他跟很多反政府组织都有联系
He's loosely affiliated with various antigovernment groups--
在军队学会的爆破技能
explosives background from a stint in the army.
吉恩  她要给你发一些东西
Jin, she was gonna to send you something.
我收到了
Yeah, I got it.
威克斯在96街和卡柳梅特河街交汇的
Wilcox owns a garage in an industrial area
工业区有个车库
where 96th meets the Calumet River.
好  让安东尼奥和琳德赛在车库跟我们碰头
All right, have Antonio and Lindsay meet us at the garage.
你待着这里  做我们的后备
You stay here. Feed us what we need.
把情况告诉格拉夫
And keep Graff in the loop.
你的意思是毫无机会吗
So you're saying zero chance?
是的
Yes.
是的  迪兰先生  我们就是这个意思
Yes, Mr. Thelan, that's what we're saying--
完全没有
Zero.
但你还是可以做一件事
But there's something you can do
一件三十年前不可能做的事
that couldn't have been done even 30 years ago.
你女儿的血型是O型阴性血
Your daughter's blood type is "O" negative.
跟楼下一个爆炸中肝脏被损坏的女孩
That's a match for another girl that got hit by the same blast
血型相符
with a ruptured liver, right down the hall.
如果不能移植新的肝脏  她就会死
She's going to die if she doesn't get a new one.
那么将有两个九岁女孩因为
That'll be two 9-year-olds killed by...
那样的事而丧命
something like this.
在正常情况下  你可以跟政府慢慢谈
Under normal circumstances, you'd have time to work
来捐献你女儿的器官
with the state to donate your daughter's organs.
今天
Today...
我请求你做出定向捐赠
I'm asking you to make a targeted donation.
如果你同意
If you agree...
你女儿的死就不会毫无意义
your daughter's death won't be meaningless.
这一点我可以肯定
That I know to be true.
你来决定吧  爸爸
It's your decision, Dad.
但如果要我说
But if it were me...
让她去吧
let's let her go.
我们时间不多  你们尽快
We need to know in minutes, not hours.
医生
Doctor...
伊莫金会希望这样的
Imogene would want this.
里面有人说话吗
Is that people talking in there?
收音机开着
A radio's on.
硝酸钡[炸药成分]检测呈阳性
It's positive for barium nitrate.
试试从屋顶攻入吧
Let's try the roof.
好  拿好光纤
All right, grab the fiber-optic.
如果灰泥落下引爆了炸弹会怎样
Now, what happens if the plaster falls and sets off the bomb?
你会第一个知道的
You'll be the first to know.
-好吧  -做你该做的
- All right. - Do your thing.
前门  侧门和后门都装上了炸药
Front, side, rear door are all rigged.
整个包围了起来
So is the roll-up.
每扇门都连着线和50加仑的桶
Wires and 50-gallon drums attached to each.
简单地说  就是不要硬闯
Short version-- do not breach.
我们可以垂降
We could rappel down.
我们不需要整个队伍都进去
All right, we don't need the whole team going in.
我来
I'll do it.
我在学校学过这门课  成绩很好
I just took the class in the academy. Aced it.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  我需要两个人  还有志愿者吗
All right, well, I need two. Any volunteers?
你
You.
不要开灯
Don't turn on any lights.
-好  -好
- Yeah. - Yeah.
来  干吧
Come on. Let's do this.
安全
Clear.
赖安·威克斯在这里
Ryan Wilcox is here...
多处枪伤
Multiple gunshot wounds.
他死了多久
How long's he been dead?
-我估计有一天  -最多
- I'd say a day? - Max.
应该是鲍威尔在灭口
It's Powell tying up more loose ends.
他们留下了很多东西
They left a lot of stuff behind.
他们没想到会被发现
They never thought it'd be found.
他们以为整个街区会被炸成个大坑
They figured this whole block would be a crater.
威克斯两个月前订购了一辆白色货车
Wilcox purchased a white cargo van about two months ago.
还订购了三个定时装置
There were three timing devices purchased.
我不是个悲观主义者  但是
I'm not a pessimist, but...
很有可能
there's a damn good shot
还有第三个汽车炸弹在一辆白色货车里
that there's a third car bomb out there in a white cargo van.
如果第二个炸弹定在晚上八点半爆炸
If the second bomb was supposed to go off at 8:30 P.M.,
那也许第三个炸弹也会定在相同的时间
maybe the third bomb was set to go off at that time as well.
-现在几点了  -七点五十五
- What time is it now? - 7:55.
还有29分钟
29 minutes and counting.
但目前没有听到任何消息
I'm listening, but I don't hear dick.
-医院停车场呢  -全面检查过了
- Hospital parking lot? - Fully vetted.
炸掉一个区太冒险了
Blowing up a district would be too risky.
炸弹很快就会被发现
A bomb would be sniffed out in seconds.
-消防站  -受害者不够多
- A firehouse? - Not enough victims.
鲍威尔想炸死警察高管和消防员
Powell wanted high-ranking police and firefighters dead.
他们中的大部分都会参加万米跑
Most of them planned on attending the 10k gala.
其他人今晚会在哪里
Yeah, and where would the rest be tonight?
总部
Headquarters.
就是那儿了
Bull's-eye.
-准备好了吗  格莉塔  -好了  医生
- You ready, Greta? - Ready, doctor.
我们让今天发生一件好事吧
Let's have one good thing come out of this day.
谢谢你
Thank you.
正在前门附近找一辆货车
Be on the lookout for a van near the front door.
吉恩  把那辆车的车牌号和照片发给所有人
Jin, text everyone the photo and plate number of the van purchased.
你们要找一辆白色伊克诺莱恩
You're looking for a white Econoline.
爆破组出发
Bomb squad en route.
我们应该让他们离开
We should have made that left.
霍斯特德  琳德赛  支路清理了吗
Halstead, Lindsay, those back roads pay off?
是的  但是因为爆炸导致
Yeah, but traffic patterns are all screwed up
-交通模式全变了  -还有15分钟
- because of the bombing. - 15 minutes out.
埃尔文  拜托告诉我点好消息
Alvin, please, give me some good news.
埃尔文
Alvin?
正在减速查看
Pulling up now.
-看见那辆车了吗  -还没
- Any eyes on the vehicle? - Not yet.
确定车是白色的吗
We're sure this van is white?
找到车了  在南面出口
Vehicle located, south side entrance.
是蓝的  不是白的  没有车牌
It's blue, not white-- no tags.
-还有12分钟  -吉恩  拆弹小组到哪了
- 12 minutes. - Jin, bomb squad update.
还有三个街区
Three blocks away.
如果鲍威尔进医院
Hey, if Powell was at the hospital
是因为他喜欢观赏自己的杰作...
because he likes to watch his handiwork...
那是什么
What's that?
-那边  -顶上吗
- Right there. - Up top?
-对  就那 看见没  -看屋顶上
- Yeah, right there. See? - Hey, on the roof.
-什么情况  -看屋顶上
- What do we got? - On the roof!
-不许动  -放下枪
- Freeze! - Drop it!
快出去  离开这幢大厦
Get out! Get out of the building!
-快  -快走
- Now! - Go! Go! Go!
走楼梯
Stairs.
他上去了
He's going up.
博伊特来了  走
There's Voight. Come on.
还有九分钟
Nine minutes!
鲍威尔在公寓楼里
We think Powell is on the apartment building!
正在追捕他
In pursuit!
拆弹小组来了  你留下看着炸弹
There's the bomb squad! You stay with the bomb!
我是21区的萨姆纳警官
Officer Sumner, District 21.
爆炸物在货车里  离爆炸时间还有8分半
Explosive is inside the van, set to go off in 8 1/2 minutes.
明白  麻烦你疏散人群
All right, clear the area, please.
回去  回去  快走
Get back! Back! Move!
疑犯上了屋顶
Suspect's entered roof!
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
掩护我
Cover me.
你赢不了的  放下武器
You can't win! Drop your weapon!
放下
Put it down!
我要抓活的
I want him alive!
起来
Get up.
我今天葬送了你多少人
How many of your boys did I put in the dirt today?
其中有你的好朋友吗
Any of 'em good friends?
你想看吗
You wanna watch?
-那就看着吧  -不要 不要
- Watch it. - No! No, no!
剩余时间
Time check!
60秒
60 seconds!
炸弹已被拆卸
Bomb dismantled.
重复  炸弹已被拆卸
Repeat-- bomb dismantled.
你的计划失败了
Plan failed.
可是我还是觉得今天过得不错
Actually, I think it was a pretty good day.
今晚干得漂亮
That's good work tonight.
博伊特
Voight.
很高兴能与你共事
Good working with you...
或者该说  很高兴能看你工作
Or, uh, watching you work, I should say.
我也是  探员
You too, Sir.
你没事吧
You all right?
生龙活虎
Solid.
是条汉子
Tough guy.
抽吸
Suction.
我当住院医生的第四年
As a senior resident,
有一次值班
I was on call.
我和创伤外科主任共事
I was working with the chief trauma surgeon.
我知道就是由他来决定
I knew he'd be the one deciding
我能否得到梦寐以求的创伤研究员职位
if I got the coveted trauma fellowship position.
但晚上九点  我们正全神贯注医治病人时
But 9:00 P.M., we were up to our eyeballs in trauma cases,
我接到电话说我父亲犯了心脏病
and I got a call that my dad suffered a heart attack.
正在送往另一家医院
Was rushed to another hospital.
夹钳
Clamp.
我问他能不能去陪陪我父亲
I asked if I could leave to be with my father.
他盯着我看  然后说
He looked me in the eye and said,
你可以走
"Yeah, you can go,
不过走了就别想要那个研究员职位了
but you'll never get the trauma fellowship."
我不敢相信这家伙居然如此冷血无情
I couldn't believe how insensitive this guy was.
心率150  血压下降
Heart rate 150. Pressure is dropping.
那晚  我们救了16个人
We saved 16 people that night,
可我父亲却去世了
but my dad passed away.
生理盐水
Heparinized saline.
夹钳拿走
Removing proximal clamp.
收缩压80
80 systolic.
76  70
76, 70.
那天  就跟今天一样
It's a day like today
我明白了那个医生为何那么做
when I understand why that surgeon did that.
这就是我们选择的生活
This is the life we've chosen.
我们能做的就在此时此刻
And what we can do is right here and now.
眼下最重要的事
It's the most important thing.
就是尽力挽救这个女孩
And that is to try and save this little girl.
手术非常顺利
The operation went as well as could be expected.
血液顺利流向了肝脏
There's, uh, good blood flow to the liver,
另一处出血也止住了
and the other bleeding has stopped.
她还有很长的路要走
She's got a long road ahead of her,
不过目前看来情况不错
but, uh, it's looking good.
消防部门仍在努力工作
Where the fire department is still working hard
清理今早八点
to clean up the mess left by a bomb
爆炸引起的混乱场面
that went off at 8 o'clock this morning,
爆炸中有18人丧生...
leaving 18 dead...
他们救出了多少幸存者
How many survivors they pull out?
听说有二十多人
I just heard over two dozen.
谢谢
Thanks.
芝加哥会重整旗鼓的
Chicago will bounce back.
当然
Yeah.
一如既往
She always does.
一有新消息我们就会告诉大家
We'll give you more information as we get it.
今晚我们会留在这里...
We're here--we're gonna be here all night...
我该先打个电话的
I should have called. I know.
你永远不必先打电话
You don't ever have to call.
我只有一个请求
I just have one request.
什么  你说
Yeah? Name it.
今晚留下来
Stay the night.
-过了今天...  -我哪儿也不去
- After today, I... - I'm not going anywhere.